# **AUROVINDHYA SRINIVASAN**

aurovindhya@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/aurovindhya-srinivasan | aurovindhya-bio.web.app

(343) 987-0655 | 1591 Lycee Place, Ottawa, ON

# **OVERVIEW**

I'm a fervent Software Developer with 2 years and 8 months of experience. My professional background is predominantly in software development, data analytics, and database management. I've worked on award-winning projects in Blockchain, Machine Learning, and Artificial Intelligence. I'm excited to advance my professional career while pursuing a master's degree in Digital Transformation and Innovation with an emphasis on Applied Data Science at the University of Ottawa.

# **EDUCATION**

# University of Ottawa, ON, Canada

(Sept 2022 - Present)

Master of Digital Transformation and Innovation Concentration in Applied Data Science

- Co-op graduate student
- Event manager at the Professional Development Club

Coursework:

Data Analytics and Business Intelligence, Fundamentals of Applied Data Science, Ethics for Design, Robotics, and Artificial Intelligence, Research Workshop for DTI

#### Anna University, India (Sri Sai Ram Institute of Technology)

(July 2016 - April 2020)

B.E Computer Science and Engineering | 8.89 CGPA

Classification: First class with distinction | University Rank: 21 | College Rank: 1

- University Rank Holder
- Yearly recipient of the Leo Muthu Merit Scholarship Awards
- Chairperson of the Department of Computer Science and Engineering
- Recipient of the Best Outgoing Student Award

#### Coursework:

Programming (C, C++, Java, Python), Database Management, Software Engineering, Artificial Intelligence, Data Analysis, Cryptography, Web Development, Machine Learning, Computer Networks, Data Structures, Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Object-Oriented Analysis and Design, Mobile Computing, Computer Architecture, Cyber Forensics, Grid and Cloud Computing

## **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Java, C, C++, Python, R, HTML, CSS, JS, PostgreSQL, MSSQL, XML, XSLT Software and Frameworks: Git, Postman, Firebase, Canva, PowerBI, Tableau, Ethereum, Pandas, Matplotlib, Numpy Soft Skills: Leadership, Teamwork, Time Management, Adaptability, Problem-Solving, Public Speaking Extracurricular: Content Writing, Poster Designing, Carnatic Music, Piano, Bharatanatyam, Painting, Audio & Video Editing

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Software Developer (Zoho Corporation, India)

(July 2020 - July 2022)

Developed significant product features for Endpoint Central with expertise in Backend development, Web development, Database Management, Data Visualization and Analytics, API Documentation, Technical Support, and Quality Assurance.

#### **Project Trainee (Zoho Corporation, India)**

(Dec 2019 - July 2020)

Real-time training on Java, RestAPIs, Servlets, Web development, and Database Management. Worked on bug fixing, developing product features, and researching potential advancements.

Aurovindhya Srinivasan (343) 987-0655

# **PROJECTS**

# P-Block (Public Blockchain) (2020)

Procurement System based on Blockchain (P-Block), my final year project, is a decentralized application used to procure/vend items safely using Ethereum, MetaMask wallet, and Truffle, linked to a real-time database on Firebase. This received the project of the year award.

#### MI-Block (Private Blockchain)

(2019)

A decentralized application to safely store and share patients' medical records, built using Hyperledger fabric. This project was developed and presented at the hackCBS 2.0, Asia's first MLH member hackathon.

#### TeachBot (Artificial Intelligence)

(2018)

An Al-based bot that assists/teaches based on the trained domain. Funded by the Innovation and Entrepreneurship Development Centre (IEDC), Sponsored by the Department of Science and Technology, Government of India.

#### Agrimeteo (Machine Learning)

(2017)

An application to predict suitable crops and water intake according to climatic and regional factors using machine learning. Fitted Multiple Linear Regression with Gradient Descent Algorithm to obtain the highest accuracy.

#### **PUBLICATION**

# Predicting Intelligence Quotient, Immunity, Blood Sugar, Defective Vision of a Fetus Using Random Forest Classification (Published in IEEE and Semantic Scholar) (2017)

The 'Random forest classification' algorithm was used to profile a fetus in various stages of its development such as pregestation, gestation, and post-gestation in order to analyze various medical metrics of the fetus and its needs at an early stage.

## CERTIFICATION

- Machine Learning Pipelines with Azure ML Studio (Coursera)
- CCNA Routing and Switching (CISCO)
- Business Administration Specialist (Salesforce)
- Programming in C++ (NPTEL)

#### UNIVERSITY EXPERIENCE

#### **Event Manager (Professional Development Club, University of Ottawa)**

Managed and conducted events at the Professional Development Club, the graduate student club at the University of Ottawa, which helps bridge the gap between students and their career goals.

#### Speaker and Tutor (Blockchain Technology Webinar, Anna University)

Conducted an online webinar series on decentralized applications for the inductees.

#### Chairperson (SINTACS '19, Anna University)

Organized the department's symposium with expertise in web development and content writing, conducted technical events, and managed the funds.

#### Student Ambassador (Pan IIT Leadership Series, Anna University)

Student Ambassador at PALS, an educational initiative benefitting engineering students.

#### Teaching Assistant and Corrector (Anna University)

Conducted seminars/webinars, addressed students' queries, and evaluated assignments.

#### Master of Ceremonies (Anna University)

Organized workshops on Women Entrepreneurship, Mobile Application Development, RedHat Linux, and Artificial Intelligence being the master of ceremonies.